Guide to the African American Museum & Library at Oakland Audiovisual Collection
African American Museum & Library at Oakland
African American Museum & Library at Oakland audiovisual collection
circa 1950s-circa 2000s
MS207
African American Museum & Library at Oakland
7.25 linear feet (5 boxes + 3 audiocassette boxes)
African American Museum & Library at Oakland (Oakland, Calif.) Oakland, CA 94612
The African American Museum & Library at Oakland Audiovisual Collection consists of 106 audiocassettes, 72 videotapes, 2 CD-Rs, and 2 seven inch reel audiotapes. The audiovisual collection consists of materials acquired by the African American Museum & Library at Oakland, and its predecessor the Northern California Center for Afro-American History & Life. The collection is organized into 16 series by format or subject, and includes recordings of significant African Americans such J. Rupert Picott and Byron Rumford, oral histories with significant African American families and civil rights leaders, and documents various topics related to African American history, culture and experience.
Access
No access restrictions. Collection is open to the public.
Access Restrictions
Materials are for use in-library only, non-circulating.
Acquisition Information
Audiovisual recordings were assembled by the African American Museum & Library at Oakland and retained in the African American Museum & Library at Oakland archives.
Biography / Administrative History
The African American Museum & Library at Oakland (AAMLO) was organized on July 2, 1965 in the home of Marcella Ford as the East Bay Negro Historical Society (EBNHS). In attendance at the first meeting were the seven founding members of the society: Marcella Ford, Jesse Ford, Eugene Lasartemay, Ruth Lasartemay, E. Harold Mason, Morrie Turner, and Madison Harvey Jr. The society’s mission was to “collect, preserve, record, and disseminate information related to the history, culture and experience, of persons of Black American and African descent, especially those in the East Bay, the State of California and throughout the West.” The society consisted of members, officers, and an executive board and included library, museum, publications and publicity, program, membership, finance, and nomination committees which met on the third Saturday of every month. Initially, the society operated as a unit of the Oakland Unified School District Volunteer Program, with members giving lectures on black history to students that would visit the library and museum. In 1970, the society moved to a storefront located at 3651 Grove Street in Oakland, California and remained there for six years before moving to 4519 Grove St., where it established a museum and library. In 1982, the society was invited into the Golden Gate Branch of the Oakland Public Library, making it the first Oakland library branch with a collection focused on African American history and culture. Following the appointment of Dr. Lawrence Crouchett as its executive director in 1988, the society changed its name to the Northern California Center for Afro-American History & Life (NCCAAHL). In 1994, the City of Oakland and the NCCAAHL merged to create the African American Museum & Library at Oakland (AAMLO).
Scope and Content of Collection
The African American Museum & Library at Oakland Audiovisual Collection, assembled by the African American Museum & Library at Oakland, contains 106 audiocassettes, 72 videotapes, 2 CD-Rs, and 2 seven inch reel audiotapes on various topics related to African American history, culture and experience. The materials date from the 1950s to 2000s. The bulk of the materials date from the 1990s
Arrangement
Series I. African American Museum & Library at Oakland (AAMLO) Series II. Binding ties Series III. Campaign spots Series IV. Church services Series V. City council meetings Series VI. Documentary film Series VII. Elihu M. Harris Series VIII. Music Series IX. Oakland Unified School District Series X. Oral histories Series XI. Radio programs Series XII. Slide shows Series XIII. Speeches and lectures Series XIV. Symposia Series XV. Television news Series XVI. Assorted
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
African Americans--California.; African Americans--Religion--History.; Civil rights--California.; Oakland (Calif.)--History.; Oakland (Calif.)--Politics and government.; Oakland (Calif.)--Race relations.; Oakland (Calif.)--Social conditions.; West Oakland (Oakland, Calif.)--History.
Collection Contents
- African American Museum & Library at Oakland (AAMLO), 1986-2004; 11 audiocassettes, 11 videotapes
  Series Scope and Content Summary
  Includes recordings related to the activities of the African American Museum & Library at Oakland (AAMLO), and its predecessors the East Bay Negro Historical Society (EBNHS) and the Northern California Center for Afro-American History & Life (NCCAAHL).
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically by subject, organization, last name, or description.
  - African American Museum & Library at Oakland, 2004-01; 1 audiocassette(s) (microcassette) (Box-folder 3)
  - African American Museum & Library at Oakland board of trustees meeting, 1995-01-21; 1 audiocassette(s) (microcassette) (Box-folder 2)
  - Crouchett, Dr. Lawrence P., speaking on "Visions toward tomorrow", 1988-02-16; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box-folder 7)
  - East Bay Negro Historical Society annual meeting, 1986-07-13; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 1)
  - East Bay rap, Northern California Center for Afro-American History & Life, circa 1990s; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 1)
  - KGO-TV Evening news segment -- Halloween at the African American Museum & Library at Oakland, 2002-10-31; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box-folder 6)
  - KNBR Public Affairs -- Kathleen Huoka, Community Relations Librarian, and May Bolton, Administrative Director of the African American Museum & Library at Oakland, 2002; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 3)
  - KRON Bay Area close-up segment – the African American Museum & Library at Oakland, 1999-04-17; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box-folder 4)
  - KSOL Community dynamics -- Donna Masters interviews Dr. Lawrence P. Crouchett on the Northern California Center for Afro-American History & Life, 1991-05-01; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 1)
  - KTOP Just a look -- Community heritage: the African American Museum & Library at Oakland [four copies], 1998-12-16; 4 videotape(s) (VHS)
  - KTOP segment -- African American Museum & Library at Oakland “Walls of pride” mural project, 2003-10-04; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box-folder 5)
  - KTOP segment -- “A journey of promise” mural at the African American Museum & Library at Oakland, circa 2003; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box-folder 4)
  - KTOP segment -- Official ground breaking of the African American Museum & Library at Oakland, 1999-10-15; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box-folder 8)
  - Lasartemay, Eugene and Mary Rudge in conversation, Northern California Center for Afro-American History & Life, 1993-03-20; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 1)
  - Lasartemay, Eugene, talk at the Oral History Office, Bancroft Library, 1986-03-18; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 2)
  - Leadership forum, African American Museum & Library at Oakland, 2003-04-25; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box-folder 8)
  - Northern California Center for Afro-American History & Life, 2004-11; 3 audiocassette(s) (microcassette) (Box-folder 3)
- Binding ties, 1991; 5 audiocassettes
  Includes interviews conducted as part of the "Binding ties: the 16th street station," a site specific installation at The Southern Pacific Railroad Station, Oakland, California, commissioned by the by The City of Oakland Cultural Arts Division in 1991. The project included music and narratives that told the story of the former Southern Pacific Railroad workers.
  Arranged alphabetically by title or description.
  - Interview conducted by Michael Sydnor with Regina Almaguer of the City of Oakland's Public Art Program on "Binding ties: the 16th street station" and public arts projects, 1991; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 2)
  - Interview with Shirley Etheridge, former Southern Pacific Railroad worker, for "Binding ties: the 16th street station" installation, 1991; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 2)
  - Interview with Florence Mays, former Southern Pacific Railroad worker, for "Binding ties: the 16th street station" installation, 1991; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 2)
  - Interview with Ray Solis, former Southern Pacific Railroad worker, for "Binding ties: the 16th street station" installation, 1991; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 2)
  - Interview with William Swinney, former Southern Pacific Railroad worker, for "Binding ties: the 16th street station" installation, 1991; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 2)
- Campaign spots, 1991; 2 audiocassette(s), 1 videotape(s)
  Includes campaign spots run on Oakland media for Ronald V. Dellums and Wilson Riles.
  Arranged alphabetically by last name.
  - Dellums, Ronald V., campaign spot [two copies], 1988; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 2)
  - Riles, Wilson campaign video for mayor of Oakland, circa 1990; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box-folder 4)
- Church services, 1957, 1977; 2 audiocassettes, 1 CD-R
  Includes recordings of church programs as collected by the African American Museum & Library at Oakland.
  - First African Methodist Episcopal Church service, 1957-06-16; 1 CD-R (Box-folder 8)
  - Picott, Dr. J. Rupert, mass meeting of the 29th observance of Afro American Month, Second Baptist Church, Los Angeles, California [two copies], 1977-02-13; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 1)
- City council meetings, 1992-1993; 4 videotapes
  Includes recordings of Oakland City Council meetings.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Oakland City Council and Board of Education inaugural ceremony, 1992-6-19; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box-folder 7)
  - Oakland City Council meeting, 1992-07-19; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box-folder 6)
  - Oakland City Council meeting, 1992-12-08; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box-folder 6)
  - Oakland City Council meeting, 1993-07-20; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box-folder 6)
- Documentary film, circa 1990s; 4 videotapes
  Includes assorted documentary film collected or gifted by the African American Museum & Library at Oakland.
  - "Black Power, Black Panthers," Ray Telles and Lewis Cohen, KQED Production, 1990; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box-folder 8)
  - “Dr. Marcella W. Ford: A great lady", circa 1990s; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box-folder 5)
  - “Honoring a great lady: Dr. Marcella W. Ford,” Griot Productions, 1996-09-15; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box-folder 7)
  - “Original sin” by Eric Barber, Sheree Bryant, Jon Colburn, Patrick Curns, Vesta Ghavamzaden, Lisa McFarland, circa 1990s; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box-folder 5)
  - "Paul Robeson: Man of Conscience," William Miles, Miles Educational Film and WNET Production, 1986-02-24; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box-folder 8)
  - "This is our town" (compilation video of Crossroads: A story of West Oakland/Pipe city dir: Richard Heegan/unknown film on Piedmont Avenue/America's castles. Castles on the Bay: Ralston Hall, Haas-Lilienthal and Dunsmuir house and gardens/Bay Area Backroads) labeled 'Steve Lavoie', circa 1990s; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box-folder 5)
- Elihu M. Harris, 1989-1994; 12 audiocassettes, 10 videotapes
  Includes recordings related to the activities of Elihu M. Harris.
  - KGO News segment Mayor Elihu M. Harris, 1989-06-16; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 3)
  - KSOL News -- General election Elihu M. Harris and Lionel Wilson, 1989-11; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 2)
  - KTOP segment -- Black History Month profiles, 1991; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box-folder 8)
  - Harris, Elihu M., Mayor’s press conference on the Oakland hills fire, 1991-10-21; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box-folder 4)
  - KCBS In depth with Mayor Elihu M. Harris, 1992-01-14; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 2)
  - KTOP Joint meeting with the City of Oakland and the City of Berkeley Insurance Commissioner John Garamendi – State of the City address, Mayor Elihu M. Harris, 1992-04-01; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box-folder 7)
  - KQED-FM Forum -- Mayor Elihu M. Harris, 1992-10-07; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 3)
  - KTOP Ask the mayor questions Mayor Elihu M. Harris, 1992-11-12; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box-folder 4)
  - KQED-FM Forum -- Mayor Elihu M. Harris, 1992-11-18; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 3)
  - KTOP Ask the mayor questions Mayor Elihu M. Harris, 1992-11-25; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box-folder 6)
  - KTOP public service announcement -- Mayor’s Toy Drive, 1992; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box-folder 7)
  - Oakland African American Chamber of Commerce breakfast with Mayor Elihu M. Harris, 1993-01; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 3)
  - KQED-FM Forum -- Mayor Elihu M. Harris, 1993-02-24; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 2)
  - KQED-FM Forum -- Mayor Elihu M. Harris, 1993-06-07; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 2)
  - KGO Newstalk with Ron Owens, interview with Mayor Elihu M. Harris, 1993-07-19; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 2)
  - KTVU Evening news segment -- Mayor Elihu M. Harris’ housing Oakland program, 1993-07; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box-folder 8)
  - KQED-FM Forum -- Mayor Elihu M. Harris, 1993-10-27; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 2)
  - KTOP Ask the mayor questions Mayor Elihu M. Harris, 1993; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box-folder 4)
  - National Coalition of Black Meeting Planners luncheon session with Mayor Elihu M. Harris, 1994-04-04; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 2)
  - Harris, Elihu M., address to an Oakland High School, circa 1990s; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 2)
  - Harris, Elihu M., Mayor’s speech on strong mayors, circa 1990s; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box-folder 6)
  - Toy drive Mayor Elihu M. Harris public service announcement, circa 1990s; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box-folder 6)
- Music, 1984-1994; 2 audiocassettes, 8 videotapes
  Includes material related to African American music or musicians.
  Arranged alphabetically by title or subject.
  - “American music through the back door,” a visual presentation by A.G. Productions, 1984-10-18; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box-folder 4)
  - Blues concert [unidentified] at Oregon State Prison, 1987-09-07; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box-folder 6)
  - KGO-TV Evening news segment -- The blues: Living legends and the music of Oakland, undated; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box-folder 5)
  - KGO-TV Evening news segment – Eli’s Mile High Club, 1990-03-29; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box-folder 8)
  - KPFA News segment -- Troyce Key obituary, 1992; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 2)
  - KRON Bay Area close-up segment – spotlight on “Sing it, when you can’t tell it", 1994; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box-folder 5)
  - "Long train running: The story of the Oakland blues," Marlon Riggs, KQED airing, 1983-02-16; 1 videotape(s) (Beta) (Box-folder 8)
  - Mayfield, Percy, undated; 1 videotape(s) (Beta) (Box-folder 8)
  - “Sing it, when you can’t tell it” sample footage, Michael Fried and Frank Crosby, 1994; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box-folder 5)
  - Unknown jazz concert, labeled 'Going to Monterey', circa 1980s; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 2)
- Oakland Unified School District, circa 1990s-2002; 3 videotapes
  Includes recordings related to the activities of the Oakland Unified School District.
  - KDOL talking with Oscar Wright about public education in Oakland, 2002-11; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box-folder 7)
  - KDOL Voluntary resolution plan: Opening doors to success, Oakland Unified School District Division of Accountability for Teaching and Learning, 2002; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box-folder 7)
  - Lewis, Reginald F., “Oakland is” presentation at Oakland Technical High School, circa 1990s; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box-folder 6)
- Oral histories, 1983-2001; 24 audiocassettes
  Includes oral history interviews conducted or assembled by staff of the African American Museum & Library at Oakland and retained in the African American Museum & Library at Oakland archives.
  - Collier, Muriel, circa 1980s; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 1)
  - De Shields, Albert, 1992-05-19; 2 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 1)
  - French, Barbara Louis Carlisle, interview conducted by Virginia Geddes, Oral Historian, in Berkeley, California, 1983-09; 2 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 2)
  - Hampton, Charles, oral history interview about moving to California from Texas, conducted by Margot Cullen in Berkeley, California, 1986-04-01; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 2)
  - Lee, Dr. Bruce oral history interview about growing up in Buffalo, New York, around the Niagara Movement and collecting Black Americana, conducted by Lawrence M. Crouchett, 1996-01-20; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 1)
  - Litzie, John, former Oakland Larks player, 1992-05-08; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 1)
  - Loving, Edith, wife of Major Walter Howard Loving, and Walter Loving Jr., conducted by Dr. Lawrence P. Crouchett, circa 1990s; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 1)
  - Piedmont Gardens retirement community Oral History class student introductions, 1983-09; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 2)
  - Proctor, Eudora, 1990-03-07; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 1)
  - Roberts, Gloria, daughter of Frederick Madison Roberts, 1992-06-05; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 1)
  - Rumford, William Byron Sr., circa 1980s; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 1)
  - Simpson, Imogene H., about growing up in Nacogdoches, Texas, conducted by Mac Calhoun, 1986-03-12; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 2)
  - Sims, Tracy, civil rights activist, interviewed by Dr. Lawrence P. Crouchett, circa 1990s; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 2)
  - Steele, Percy H. Jr., about the Bay Area Urban League, circa 1990s; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 1)
  - Washington, Mary Beth, interview conducted by Joyce Kraus in Berkeley, California, 1984-01-08; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 2)
  - White, Clinton W., former justice on the California Court of Appeal, and James White, interview conducted by Mr. Robert Haynes, 1997-08-30; 3 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 3)
- Radio programs, 1976-1995; 8 audiocassettes, 1 CD-R
  Includes copies of radio programs recorded by, or gifted to, staff of the African American Museum & Library at Oakland on various topics related to African American history, culture and experience.
  - KCBS News segment -- Affordable housing, 1993-07-14; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 5)
  - KCBS News segment -- From where we came: Life before the Civil Rights movement, 1989; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 1)
  - KDIA Mind your money with Cheryl Broussard, Dennis Kimbro guest, 1995-02-03; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 2)
  - KDIA William “Rosko” Mercer broadcasts, 1962—1963; 1 CD-R (Box-folder 8)
  - KPFA News -- Dr. Frances Cress Welsing about the First Annual Melanin Conference, 1987; 3 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 1)
  - KPFA News segment with Crystal Page, 1993-07-19; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 2)
  - KQED-FM Forum -- Chappell Hayes tribute, 1993-02-03; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 2)
  - KSAN Radio -- Now it can be told: MK-Ultra/CIA mind control, 1976-08-09; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 2)
  - Morning radio interview with Walter Sisulu, 1990-01; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 2)
- Speeches and lectures, 1980-2000; 10 audiocassettes, 6 videotapes, 2 audiotapes
  Includes recordings of lectures, speeches, keynote addresses and public talks on various topics related to African American history, culture and experience.
  Arranged alphabetically by name, organization, title, or description.
  - Acty, Ruth, oral history reception Berkeley Historical Society, 2001-12-18; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box-folder 7)
  - Ajirotutu, Dr. Cheryl, talk at the East Bay Negro Historical Society, 1985-02-25; 3 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 1)
  - Baptist Ministers Union of Oakland presidential banquet, speakers Dr. Jeremiah Wright with Sheila Robinson, 1995-03-31; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 2)
  - Beckles, Hilary, lecture on the transatlantic slave trade, University of the West Indies, UNESCO, 2000-01; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box-folder 4)
  - Jackson, Jesse, keynote address to the Congressional Black Caucus Foundation, 1988-09-17; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 2)
  - Lemke-Santangelo, Gretchen, on the history of Blacks in Berkeley [Side A] Dr. Willie Collins on the history of West Oakland [Side B], circa 1990s; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 1)
  - Rockwell speech, undated; 1 audiotape(s) (7 inch reel) (Box-folder 2)
  - Rumford, William Byron Sr., freeway dedication ceremony, 1980-11-15; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 1)
  - Saafir, Imam Saadiq, speaks on "From Black Muslim to Muslim", circa 1980s; 2 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 2)
  - Speech in auditorium/Nazi Party member speaker/questions and debate in classroom, undated; 1 audiotape(s) (7 inch reel) (Box-folder 1)
  - Unknown speaker on life cell detoxification, unlabeled, circa 1980s; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 3)
  - Vazant, Iyanla reading and talk at Marcus Book Store, Oakland, California, 1996-07-16; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box-folder 4)
  - Vazant, Iyanla reading and talk at Marcus Book Store, Oakland, California [two copies], 1999-05-04; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box-folder 4)
  - Wilson, E. Dotson, Chief Clerk of the California State Assembly, undated; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box-folder 5)
- Slide show, circa 1990s; 3 audiocassettes
  Includes audio recordings of slide show presentations on the history of Oakland’s African American community.
  - Oakland’s Afro-American heritage play slide show narration, circa 1990s; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 1)
  - Oakland's Black community today slide show narration, circa 1990s; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 1)
  - Oakland in ebony: 1840-1950 slide show narration, circa 1990s; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 1)
- Symposia, 1989-1995; 7 audiocassettes, 2 videotapes
  Includes recordings of conferences or symposiums organized on various topics related to African American history, culture and experience.
  - Bittersweet triumph: The African American experience in WWII symposium, 1995; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 1)
  - From our hands and hearts: African American history of Alameda, Alameda Historical Society, circa 1990s; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box-folder 5)
  - The lure of California to Black Americans symposium, The Oakland Museum, 1989-02-04; 3 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 1)
  - Pioneer Black educators symposium, Stanford University, 1990-04-23; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box-folder 7)
  - Visions towards tomorrow: The history of the East Bay Afro American community from 1852-present symposium, The Oakland Museum, 1989-03-04; 3 audiocassette(s) (Box-folder 2)
- Television news broadcasts, 1986-2006; 11 videotapes
  Includes copies of assorted television news broadcasts on various topics recorded by, or gifted to, staff of the African American Museum & Library at Oakland on various topics related to African American history, culture and experience.
  - KTOP segment -- Black History Month profiles, 1991; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box-folder 8)
  - CNN Evening news segment with Crystal Page -- Blacks elected, 1992; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box-folder 7)
  - KGO-TV Good morning Bay Area segment -- Mayor Lionel Wilson addresses drug problems, 1986-08-29; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box-folder 6)
  - KTOP Culture chat “Black History Month”, 1991; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box-folder 7)
  - KTVU Mornings on 2 segment -- Bob McKenzie reports on Oakland, 1993-04-14; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box-folder 7)
  - KTVU Mornings on 2 segment -- Oakland’s reaction to Rodney King’s verdict [three copies], 1993-04; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box-folder 5)
  - KRON News program -- WWII Black Navy veterans and the Port Chicago story, circa 1990s; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box-folder 8)
  - Living Room T.V. segment on Elizabeth T. Flood, Lewis Cultural Center, 2006-04; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box-folder 7)
- Assorted, 1971-2005; 11 videotapes
  Includes assorted recordings assembled by, created by, or gifted to, staff of the African American Museum & Library at Oakland on various topics.